Before Sam was murdered, he told Molly he'd love and protect her forever.
Ghost is a fantasy, drama, thriller film directed by Jerry Zucker.
After a young man is murdered, his spirit stays behind to warn his lover
of impending danger, with the help of a reluctant psychic.
Sam Wheat, played by Patrick Swayze.
Molly Jensen, played by Demi Moore.
Oda Mae Brown, played by Whoopi Goldberg.
Carl Bruner, played by Tony Goldwyn.
Subway Ghost, played by Vincent Schiavelli.
Willie Lopez, played by Rick Aviles.
Ghost is a 1990 American supernatural romance film directed by Jerry Zucker, written by Bruce Joel
Rubin, and starring Patrick Swayze, Demi Moore, Whoopi Goldberg, and Tony Goldwyn.
It focuses on Sam Wheat (Swayze), a murdered banker, whose ghost sets out to save his girlfriend, Molly Jensen (Moore),
from the person who arranged his murder (Goldwyn) – through the help of the psychic Oda Mae Brown (Goldberg).
Ghost was theatrically released on July 13, 1990 by Paramount Pictures, to commercial success, grossing $505 million against a budget of $22–23
million and emerging as the highest-grossing film of 1990 and at the time of its release, was the third-highest-grossing film of all time.
The film was a sleeper hit, which unexpectedly outperformed several
blockbuster action films released during that summer.
Its success extended to the home video market, and it was the
most rented film of 1991 in the United States.
The film initially received mixed reviews from critics, with praise
going towards the score and performances of the cast.
Ghost earned five nominations at the 63rd Academy Awards: Best Picture, Best Original Score, Best Film
Editing, and winning Best Supporting Actress for Goldberg and Best Original Screenplay for Rubin.
The film explores themes of fortune teller, corruption,
soulmates, afterlife, money transfer.
The tone is mind_bending and emotional and intense.